[narrator] After he parts ways with Killua
in order to stop the sorting process,
Gon finds himself under attack
by new Chimera Ants.
[Gon] An owl and a bat?
They're both nocturnal creatures.
Hunters of the night.
Bring it.
[groans]
The owl's feathers?
The bat's wings are so loud,
I couldn't hear the owl coming.
[opening theme music playing]
[singer singing in Japanese]
[singer singing in English]
COMBINATION X AND X EVOLUTION
[Owl Ant laughs]
My ears can pick up sounds
-[wings flapping loudly]
-[Gon] From the right this time.
[groans]
[Bat Ant] All that aura
still won't help you.
We rule the darkness.
[Gon] I need a new approach.
If the owl is acting as backup,
I've gotta focus on the sound
of the bat's wings.
[loud flapping]
Right after the owl attacks,
the bat strikes.
-[wings flap]
-Now.
[gasps] I missed?
But my timing was perfect.
Is it echolocation?
Damn. I missed again?
[Bat Ant] He's correctly guessing
the direction of my attacks.
[Gon] It seems the bat uses echolocation
to anticipate the timing
and angle of my attack.
[Owl Ant] Can I assist?
[Bat Ant] Hold on. I'll try
getting closer as quietly as I can.
It's all gone.
[Bat Ant] Now without flapping.
-A Dive Bomb!
-[Gon] No way.
Your wings are nothing like the owl's,
so I can hear you
slicing through the air as you fall.
[Bat Ant] Well, go on.
Show me your ultimate attack.
No reaction? [laughs]
Pathetic human ears.
[Bat Ant gasps] That noise! I can't see.
I have to escape.
Not so fast.
but when it comes to attacking with sound,
I can't be beat.
[Meleoron] This is why
they're such a great team.
They strike with sound
and finish with brawn.
[laughs]
Well, kid?
[Gon] Do I plug my ears? No.
If I limit my hearing,
my reaction time will suffer.
I know. Gyo.
[Owl Ant] Huh? Glowing eyes?
No, it's aura.
He's focusing on sight instead of hearing.
[Bat Ant] Let's give him another.
Nauseating Noise!
[grunts]
Water significantly weakens
the energy of sound.
-[high-pitched ringing]
-[Gon groaning]
when stalking their prey.
they'll take me down
before I can even find them.
[Meleoron] In terms of latent aura,
this kid has a clear advantage.
Even after all those hits,
he's still unharmed.
But his capability is irrelevant.
Without a strategy,
he's just a moving target.
[Owl Ant] The fool must think that
staying really close to me all the time
will prevent the sonic attacks.
[Bat Ant] No such luck.
-[high-pitched ringing]
-[groaning]
If I use Rock, I know can defeat this one,
but if I do, the bat might run off
and warn the other Ants.
[Owl Ant laughs]
To me, a starry night is as bright as day.
As long as I'm not in pitch darkness,
I can see you
without needing to rely on my hearing.
That means that if I cover my ears…
[Meleoron] So the kid has shrouded
his entire body in aura
to avoid major damage.
But that greatly reduces
the strength of his attacks,
making it impossible
to stand against them.
Here!
They always take positions
on opposite sides
to avoid both being targeted at once.
…the bat is behind me.
Then the real wall was behind me.
[Owl Ant] He turned our teamwork
against us?
[gasps]
Damn! [panting]
-[Gon] Show me Rock!
-Huh?
-Janken…
-Why, you…
-[gasps]
-Rock!
[gasps]
[Gon] I made sure to knock you west.
Go back to the NGL!
[Meleoron] That was incredible.
I see. So that's his signature move.
I take it back. He can be useful.
But how do I proceed?
Diego's been dethroned,
and now soldiers, all of them brainwashed,
Can't be.
We all saw the soldiers
try to kill everyone.
Warn the people in other areas. Go! Hurry!
Meow, it was from the southeast this time.
Some of my puppets have been stopped.
He's fast.
Well, whoever they are,
they're unpredictable.
An assassin?
But it seems like
they're acting on their own.
A decoy?
[groans] This is so annoying.
I wanna kill them!
[violin music playing]
[Shaiapouf] It may all be
an act to draw you out,
My anguish is intoxicating
as I wallow in my dilemma.
[Shaiapouf] The answer is quite simple.
Our duty is to protect the King.
We must focus on that
and let the other Ants handle the rest.
[door opens]
[Leol] Is it our turn?
When we were injured and on the run
from the Hunters, you took us in,
Someone is out there
running around and disabling my puppets.
Can you go and kill them?
[Leol] You can count on me.
Perfect. Take this.
We can't use telepathy, you see.
That's how I'll give you updates
on their location.
[Leol] Right.
we can be sure that they'll be
working hard to carry out their mission.
[Shaiapouf] However,
they may be waiting to betray us.
[chuckles] And in that case,
[Killua panting]
The closest village to here
is at two o'clock,
and the next ones are at eight and ten.
Should I just skip them and head for Taba,
40 kilometers away?
[Knuckle groans] This is bad.
Must have slipped past
the Hunters that replaced us.
Not bad,
but Colt has confirmed that unfortunately
none of them were squadron leaders.
According to him, there are eight of them
left that would be considered aggressive.
They've encountered four so far,
but every last one of them was
able to avoid being killed or captured.
Cheetu is going to East Gorteau
for a reason.
I'm willing to bet that
he knows the King is there.
I'm positive he's choosing
to return to the service of the King
in order to increase his own power.
My ability is still in effect
for the time being,
and I'm a lot stronger than he is,
but if we let him slip away from us
and he can gain even more power
before we meet again,
then all bets are off.
Plus if we allow any more Ants like him
to join up with the King's forces,
then we'll never be able
to draw the Royal Guard away.
Still wanna stop me? Do your best.
But I'm not gonna make it easy for you.
Uh…
First we should contact Mr. Morel.
If worse comes to worst,
he'll need to have adequate time
to find replacements for us.
I'm coming with you.
This should increase the odds
of us capturing that Ant.
[chuckles]
It's Knuckle. Something's come up.
Yes, I guess so. Probably.
[Morel] Fools!
I thought I told you to send Likke.
There's no one
more suited for this than him.
Huh?
Guess the review board didn't send over
the Hunter that we requested.
And who did they send instead?
Some Hunter I've never heard of,
probably just a temp.
A temp?
You mean hired Hunters
who only take assigned jobs
through the Hunter Association?
Not surprisingly, they have less talent.
Damn it!
I should have just
gone to talk to Likke myself.
Come on now. Stop being so foolish.
Bear in mind
that if we go over the board's head,
the Chairman is the one who's going to get
saddled with all of the blame.
He had to argue with the board
just to get us here.
I can't imagine it would go well for him.
Yeah, but they don't understand
the situation here.
It's based on donations
and who did what way back when.
Yes, but that's no surprise.
The board has always been inflexible.
How the hell can you be so relaxed, huh?
If we underestimate the squadron leaders,
we'll pay dearly for it.
Fact of the matter is
these things are tough,
that the Vice-Chairman's faction
is bribing the board?
Is that right?
There's no evidence of that happening.
[laughs] You think
they're stupid enough to get caught?
Look at the facts.
The squadron leaders,
every single one of them they've faced,
has escaped alive.
If we don't succeed,
the Chairman will be blamed.
He'll take the fall for everything.
The Vice-Chairman's supporters
will do anything to guarantee that.
The more victims the Ants claim,
the louder the voices
screaming for his resignation.
Meanwhile, they're just kicking back
in their office chairs.
[Knov] Hmm.
If we can take out the King,
but five million people are already dead,
then we've totally failed!
When he devised this plan,
he was fully aware of the consequences.
He knew exactly how much time
assuring victory would take
and how many casualties.
[Morel grunts angrily]
Five million's on the low end.
That's still too high.
[cell phone ringing]
[Morel] Mr. Marcos?
What?
[Marcos] The damn phones
have been ringing nonstop.
And that's not all.
Rumors of a coup d'état are flying around.
It's been discovered that mass murders
are taking place all over the country.
It's no rumor.
I mean, it's actually happening.
What is going on here?
Tell me, are you responsible?
We haven't done anything.
Did the public find out about the sorting?
-[alarm blaring]
-[gasps] We'll talk later on.
-Now go back to your office immediately.
-[Knov] Morel.
-Huh?
-[line disconnects]
Good evening. The dearly beloved
leader of our land, Diego,
has an urgent announcement to make.
[over speaker]
To ensure our great leader's message
will be heard clearly
throughout the nation,
we request that
all relay speakers in all regions
be turned to maximum volume.
All televisions and radios should be on
and the volume raised
to its maximum setting.
that would foment rebellion.
I ask you not to leave your residence
for any reason.
Lock your doors.
The soldiers of my special forces
will soon be visiting your residences
That happened too quickly.
It would give them
all the excuse they needed
[slow pop music playing]
[scoffs] Yeah, bring it on.
Tanks, jets,
whatever the hell else you've got.
[upbeat music playing]
[Gon] Next time, "Tracking and Pursuit."
-Ninety-eight…
-[Killua] Ninety-nine…
-[both] One hundred!
-[Gon] Thanks, everyone.
[Killua] For helping us reach
100 episodes.